600 S. Dobson Rd #149, Mesa, AZ 85202

Home: 9284863281 • Cell: 9284863281 fmatthew40@gmail.com

Github profile: https://github.com/fmatthew40

# **SUMMARY**

Team oriented full stack web developer with superb communication skills, diligence, and dependability. Experience working with HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, SQL, NoSQL, express.js, node.js, and Git.

### HIGHLIGHTS

| Advanced Writing Skills                           | Mentor Teacher                        |  |
|---|---------------------------------------|--|
| Teaching Certificate with English Second Language | Yearbook Developer                    |  |
| Endorsement                                       | Differentiated instruction specialist |  |
| Critical thinker                                  | "Jump Rope for Heart" Coordinator     |  |
| Writing Map Specialist                            | AVID Trained                          |  |
| IEP knowledge                                     | Microsoft Excel proficiency           |  |
| Utilizes Thinking Maps                            | Quick learner                         |  |
| Team player                                       |                                       |  |

## ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Students had Highest Proficiency in Math and ELA in school on NWEA and AZMerit last 2 years Mentored other teachers and student teachers Winning N.O.V.A. Essay contest winner from my class.

Excellence Award Winner

Managed classes of up to 36 students.

Facilitated small reading and writing groups, phonics groups and math groups for grade 5.

600 S. Dobson Rd #149, Mesa, AZ 85202

Home: 9284863281 • Cell: 9284863281 fmatthew40@gmail.com

Github profile: https://github.com/fmatthew40

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### LIBERTY ARTS ACADEMY

#### MESA, AZ

#### 5th Grade Teacher 06/2018 to Current

Observed and assessed student performance and kept thorough records of progress. Managed classrooms of 25-36 students. Organized and ran after school clubs

Implemented a variety of teaching methods such as lectures, discussions and demonstrations.

Provided Mentoring to other Teachers

Established clear objectives for all lessons, units and projects.

Encouraged students to persevere with challenging tasks.

Set and communicated ground rules for the classroom based on respect and personal responsibility. Tutored children individually and in small groups to help them with difficult subjects.

Scheduled and held parent-teacher conferences to keep parents up-to-date on children's academic performance.

Established positive relationships with students, parents, fellow teachers and school administrators. Collaborated with other staff members to plan and schedule lessons promoting learning and student engagement.

Employed a broad range of instructional techniques to retain student interest and maximize learning.

Implemented remedial programs for students requiring extra assistance.

Created lesson plans in accordance with state curriculum and school-wide curriculum standards.

Differentiated instruction according to student ability and skill level.

#### HAVASU PREPARATORY ACADEMY

Lake Havasu City, AZ

## 5th Grade Teacher 08/2012 to 06/2018

Observed and assessed student performance and kept thorough records of progress. Managed classrooms of 25-36 students. Organized and ran "Jump Rope for Heart" event.

Implemented a variety of teaching methods such as lectures, discussions and demonstrations.

Organized a yearbook club to work on and finish the school's yearbook.

Established clear objectives for all lessons, units and projects.

Encouraged students to persevere with challenging tasks.

600 S. Dobson Rd #149, Mesa, AZ 85202

Home: 9284863281 • Cell: 9284863281 fmatthew40@gmail.com

Github profile: https://github.com/fmatthew40

Set and communicated ground rules for the classroom based on respect and personal responsibility. Tutored children individually and in small groups to help them with difficult subjects.

Scheduled and held parent-teacher conferences to keep parents up-to-date on children's academic performance.

Established positive relationships with students, parents, fellow teachers and school administrators. Collaborated with other staff members to plan and schedule lessons promoting learning and student engagement.

Employed a broad range of instructional techniques to retain student interest and maximize learning.

Implemented remedial programs for students requiring extra assistance. Created lesson plans in accordance with state curriculum and school-wide curriculum standards.

Differentiated instruction according to student ability and skill level

#### LAKE HAVASU UNIFIED SCHOOL DISTRICT

Lake Havasu City, AZ

Fifth Grade Teacher 08/2011 to 06/2012 Observed and assessed student performance and kept thorough records of progress.

Managed classroom of 25 students.

Implemented a variety of teaching methods such as lectures, discussions and demonstrations.

Established clear objectives for all lessons, units and projects. Encouraged students to persevere with challenging tasks.

Set and communicated ground rules for the classroom based on respect and personal responsibility.

Tutored children individually and in small groups to help them with difficult subjects. Scheduled and held parent-teacher conferences to keep parents up-to-date on children's academic performance. Established positive relationships with students, parents, fellow teachers and school administrators. Collaborated with other staff members to plan and schedule lessons promoting learning and student engagement. Employed a broad range of instructional techniques to retain student interest and maximize learning. Implemented remedial programs for students requiring extra assistance. Created lesson plans in accordance with state curriculum and school-wide curriculum standards. Differentiated instruction according to student ability and skill level.

#### **EDUCATION**

| MASTER OF SCIENCE: ELEMENTARY EDUCATION/ENGLISH SECOND LANGUAGE | 2014 |
|---|------|
| NorthCentral University, Mesa, AZ, United States                |      |
| 3.9 GPA   |      |
| Coursework in Elementary Education and English Second Language  |      |
| BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: BUSINESS FINANCE                           | 2008 |
| Northern Arizona University, Flagstaff, AZ, United States       |      |
| Certificate in Investments                                      |      |
| Phi Theta Kappa Member  |      |

600 S. Dobson Rd #149, Mesa, AZ 85202

Home: 9284863281 • Cell: 9284863281 fmatthew40@gmail.com

Github profile: https://github.com/fmatthew40

| Coursework in Business Finance, Investments, Education             |  |
|--|--|
| CERTIFICATES   |  |
| Arizona Standard Elementary Education 1-8, 04/03/2015 – 08/08/2021 |  |
| First Aide Certification, current                                  |  |
| CPR/ADE Certification, current                                     |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |
|  |  |